OLEG NOSYREV

Seattle, WA 98109 ♥ (425)625-1273 ■

ymmy1.github.io/

linkedin.com/in/oleg-nosyrev in

<u>ABOUT</u>

Middle Front End Engineer with over 9 years of industry experience, specializing in **React, JavaScript, and TypeScript**. I live to learn. By that I mean I love taking on new and exciting challenges to expand my horizon on a day to day basis. I make the extra effort to ensure that I understand what I'm doing/working on. There is a special place in my heart for code, so I take any opportunity I have to expand my knowledge base, and learn more.

WORK EXPERIENCE

FRONT END ENGINEER

Self-Employed | 07/2023 - Present | (Remote)

- Developed and maintained <u>Next.js</u> applications on Upwork, ensuring timely completion and client satisfaction.
- Provided front-end solutions using <u>HTML, CSS</u>, <u>JavaScript</u>, and <u>TypeScript</u> for Fiverr clients, meeting strict deadlines and exceeding expectations.
- Completed front-end projects utilizing various technologies for Freelancer clients, <u>communicating</u> <u>effectively</u> to understand requirements and deliver outstanding results.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER – FRONT END

Itential | 11/2021 - 05/2023 | Atlanta, GA (Remote)

- Responsible for 2 applications used directly by Fortune500 network engineers
- Improved the page load speed by 45%.
- Reduced the number of bug tickets at start by 75%.
- Led a project for major, minor, and patch upgrades
- Planned and architected a new project from zero.
- Led a team of 4 front-end developers.
- Technologies used throughout the career: <u>React</u>, <u>Emotion</u>, <u>CSS</u>, <u>JavaScript and TypeScript</u>.

FRONT END ENGINEER

Minority Programmers Associates | 04/2021 – 07/2021 Contract | Washington D.C. (Remote)

- Working in a team of Designers, Frond End and Back End Developers, Developing and Prototyping Projects in React/Next.js
- Designing and implementing user interfaces (UIs)

FRONT END DEVELOPER

Evergreen Athlethics | 11/2018 – 12/2021 | Woodinville, WA

- Built, hosted and managed a business website that multiplied the volume of new customers to the gym by more than 300%.
- Build a User Panel together with an Admin Panel for future maintenance

SKILLS

React (LinkedIn top 20%),
CSS (LinkedIn top 5%),
JavaScript (LinkedIn top 15%),
HTML (LinkedIn top 15%),
SASS/SCSS, Tailwind, Vue is TypeScript, Next is

SASS/SCSS, Tailwind, Vue.js, TypeScript, Next.js, npm, yarn, Webpack, babel, Docker, CI/CD, Git, Jira, RESTful API, Bootstrap, Vite, Nuxt.js, Figma, some Python, Django, C, SQLite, postgreSQL, Amazon Web Services, Azure and more.

EDUCATION

HARVARD UNIVERSITY

Web Development with Python and JavaScript

Graduated November 2020 | Cambridge, MA

Curriculum: HTML, CSS | Git | Python | Django | SQL Models and Migrations | JavaScript | User Interfaces | Testing, Ci/CD | Scalability and Security

Computer Science 50

Graduated June 2020 | Cambridge, MA

Curriculum: Scratch | C | Arrays | Algorithms | Memory | Data Structures | Python | SQL | Android / IOS Development | Game Development | Web Development

UNIVERSITY OF WASHINGTON

Front-End Web Development

Graduated August 2019 | Seattle, WA

Curriculum: HTML5 And CSS3 Foundations | Web Forms, JavaScript And Responsive Design | Application Programming Interface (APIs) | Vue.js

VISAGINAS CITY COLLEGE (VTVMPC)

3-Year-Degree

Graduated June 2015 | Visaginas, Lithuania Curriculum Score: 96/100

Curriculum Score: 96/100

ONLINE COURSES

ALGOEXPERT

Frontend Expert Course

Graduated November 2023

Description: 23h total of lectures, 84h total of coding practices and 65 minutes total of guizes assestments.

Curriculum: HTML, CSS | JavaScript | DOM Manipulation | React | React Components | React Hooks | Web Fundamentals